<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fatratkiller Blog</title>
    <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fatratkiller Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 08:53:13 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://fatratkiller.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Theory of New National Development Based on DAO</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/a-theory-of-new-national-development-based-on-dao/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 08:53:13 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/a-theory-of-new-national-development-based-on-dao/</guid>
      <description>According to the Book of Genesis, Noah&amp;rsquo;s descendants built a magnificent city near Babylon. They also built a tower of Babel to make a name for themselves. God was offended by the arrogance of man and decided to make a confusion of tongues so that they could not speak to one another. There is no mention in Genesis of whether God destroyed the tower, but in many deductive versions God did so.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data   to   Earn and VeData (3, 3)</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/data-to-earn-and-vedata-3-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 08:50:18 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/data-to-earn-and-vedata-3-3/</guid>
      <description>https://www.bing-ventures.com/insights/29--Data-to-Earn-and-veData-3-3-&#xA;It is now widely believed that the fourth industrial revolution will be driven by data. Blockchain technology, which makes data self-aware, has become a new asset class. The data of today&amp;rsquo;s world is already large enough to increase the digital dependence of humans and thus generate more data. So the world is scrambling to regulate the use, storage and privacy of data. The data DAO is born from this. Data DAOs represent a post-industrial opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Subscribe to My Web3 Airdrop Calendar</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/how-to-subscribe-to-my-web3-airdrop-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 16:42:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/how-to-subscribe-to-my-web3-airdrop-calendar/</guid>
      <description>Staying updated with the latest airdrop events is crucial for every crypto enthusiast. Our Airdrop Calendar is designed to help you keep track of these events seamlessly. Please star this repository to get more guidlines on how to get this airdrops: https://github.com/fatratkiller/web3-airdrop-calendar-generator&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s how you can generate the ICS file for the calendar, use it with Google Calendar(or other Calendar), and subscribe to it on your Apple device.&#xA;Generating the ICS File</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Ockham’s Razor to Discover DeFi2.0 Metagovernance Value</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/using-ockhams-razor-to-discover-defi2.0-metagovernance-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 08:51:11 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/using-ockhams-razor-to-discover-defi2.0-metagovernance-value/</guid>
      <description>Metagovernance refers to the decentralized decision-making organisation exercised certain control by the fragmented and modular interactive governance model. The reason why I think the era of DeFi2.0 is far away is that the definition of DeFi2.0 should not be limited to a simple nested combination of revenue products. The true use case DeFi2.0 would be to transfer the benefits of liquidity from the token staking incentive model to the broader metagovernance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakdown and Innovation of Web3 Asset Management Protocol</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/breakdown-and-innovation-of-web3-asset-management-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 08:58:52 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/breakdown-and-innovation-of-web3-asset-management-protocol/</guid>
      <description>The lifeline of the asset management agreement is determined by its overhead. For the Protocol to be sustainable in the long term, DeSyn Protocol needs to obtain sustainable fees from user adoption. Has the DeSyn Protocol done enough to ensure its success? To answer this question, we need to fully understand how the DeSyn Protocol has evolved. This article will describe the state of DeSyn Protocol mobility and the reasons for promoting the use of this asset management Protocol.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aura Network: Brewing the Next Cycle of the NFT Boom</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/aura-network-brewing-the-next-cycle-of-the-nft-boom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 10:25:23 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/aura-network-brewing-the-next-cycle-of-the-nft-boom/</guid>
      <description>NFTS make our digital lives more virtual and allow us to accomplish everything in the virtual world that we can&amp;rsquo;t do in real life. The next-generation public Aura Network incorporates digital experiences to enable a rich, real-time, globally connected virtual environment that provides a new underlying environment for users to work, play, collaborate, and socialize in a whole new way. The market currently needs a decentralized underlying infrastructure that can meet the needs of complex NFT applications, and Aura Network is designed as a creative platform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Derivative Protocol That Focuses on Cross Chain Staking</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/a-derivative-protocol-that-focuses-on-cross-chain-staking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 09:25:16 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/a-derivative-protocol-that-focuses-on-cross-chain-staking/</guid>
      <description>With the success of Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s Merge, Staking is Staking in a POS network from POW to POS, and Staking is Staking in a POS network, where Staking is Staking in the security of the network by Staking a token in the network. However, an asset that is otherwise locked cannot be used within a certain period of time. However, a derivative Staking frees up the liquidity of an asset, boosting its utilization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Will Social Protocols Come of Age?</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/when-will-social-protocols-come-of-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 09:25:17 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/when-will-social-protocols-come-of-age/</guid>
      <description>https://medium.com/@BingVentures/when-will-social-protocols-come-of-age-f47049d947c9&#xA;A sufficiently decentralized network must be one where users can communicate with each other anytime, anywhere, in real time, which means that censorship resistance and security are at the core of the network. At the same time, users must have complete control over their identity (username), data (messages) and social graph (relationships with others). If a third party controls either, they can prevent the two users from communicating. Developers must also be free to build applications with unrestricted access to the network.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Ideas for Web3 Wallets</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/social-ideas-for-web3-wallets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 16:04:22 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/social-ideas-for-web3-wallets/</guid>
      <description>We can get away from the virtual space, but we will never get away from the social. The Web3 social circle is expanding, and the integration with the Web2 social model is accelerating, and one or more global distributed social networks that are more resistant to censorship can be expected. At that point, more value elements will be released in this vast network, and the crypto world will no longer be a marginal cultural region.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Consensus Engine That Fuses the Cosmos and Ethereum</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/a-consensus-engine-that-fuses-the-cosmos-and-ethereum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 12:29:02 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/a-consensus-engine-that-fuses-the-cosmos-and-ethereum/</guid>
      <description>Ethereum and Cosmos have always had a huge number of developers and users, but there has been a lack of a project that really brings the two together. Kava, a highly secure, lightening fast Layer 1 blockchain, combines the two most commonly used permissionless execution environments into a single, scalable, developer-optimized network. It has successfully built a bridge between Ethereum and Cosmos, the world&amp;rsquo;s two largest blockchain developer communities. It will also open up endless possibilities for Ethereum and Cosmos.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metis Adds Variables to Layer 2</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/metis-adds-variables-to-layer-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 09:11:52 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/metis-adds-variables-to-layer-2/</guid>
      <description>With the rapid growth of Ethereum, the proliferation of on-chain businesses has also caused the blockchain network to be overloaded, and on-chain transactions to become slow and expensive. The Defi midsummer in 2020 and the NFT frenzy last year further exacerbated the congestion level of the Ethereum network and severely limited the large-scale development of the ecosystem on the Ethereum chain. Based on this, the expansion of Ethereum has always been concerned by the market, and Rollup expansion technology is the most popular two-layer expansion scheme in the market.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Implications of Terra’s Failure for Public Chain Projects</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/the-implications-of-terras-failure-for-public-chain-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:52:41 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/the-implications-of-terras-failure-for-public-chain-projects/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: The flexible redemption mechanism and interest rate design of algorithmic stablecoin should come first. Similarly, the algorithm should be kept in a box and not reduced to a growth gimmick for network effects.&#xA;Algorithmic stablecoins are stablecoins that rely entirely on algorithms to regulate supply and demand to create and maintain currency values. Does the collapse of Terra/UST, the largest and most mainstream algorithmic stablecoin system on the market, mean that algorithmic stablecoin is a false proposition?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Actively Managed on Chain Asset Protocols</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/the-future-of-actively-managed-on-chain-asset-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 09:25:41 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/the-future-of-actively-managed-on-chain-asset-protocols/</guid>
      <description>Like Stablecoin, on-chain asset management has been one of the first blockchain scenarios to land. The DAO&amp;rsquo;s organizational structure naturally removes organizational barriers to decentralized asset management. Enzyme, a pioneer of multi-chain asset management protocols, was created in 2016. More importantly, it can use tokens to incentivise asset issuers and liquidity participants to tap into more decentralized financial scenarios. From flatter investment decision-making systems, to incentives to participate in product beta versions, to the formation of vast armies of capital in the upcoming metaverse.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking the Investment Logic of Public Chain With Open Sewer Model</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/rethinking-the-investment-logic-of-public-chain-with-open-sewer-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 11:19:34 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/rethinking-the-investment-logic-of-public-chain-with-open-sewer-model/</guid>
      <description>Warren Buffett&amp;rsquo;s longtime business partner, Charlie Munger, has continued to express his distrust of cryptocurrencies in media interviews. He called the &amp;ldquo;crypto craze&amp;rdquo; a &amp;ldquo;massive act of stupidity.&amp;rdquo; He described cryptocurrency as &amp;ldquo;like an open sewer full of evil creatures&amp;rdquo; and hoped investors would never touch or buy it. I can well understand the source of this sentiment and believe that his claim is valid. As an early supporter of the crypto industry, I have often been more concerned about the price of cryptocurrencies than I am about the technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why does the L1&amp;L2 hybrid modular public chain go further?</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/why-does-the-l1l2-hybrid-modular-public-chain-go-further/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:19:34 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/why-does-the-l1l2-hybrid-modular-public-chain-go-further/</guid>
      <description>How SKALE works&#xA;There is still no perfect blockchain to this day, and neither is Ethereum. This is mainly due to the so-called &amp;ldquo;blockchain triangle dilemma&amp;rdquo; - the inability to achieve a harmonious balance between scalability, decentralization and security. Yet, there is no denying that Ethereum currently has the strongest and most active ecosystem and also the highest adoption rate to date. SKALE is built on top of Ethereum, but it is much more than that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Perspective on Synthetix and Mirror: An Exploration of DeFi Synthetic AssetClass Project Governance Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/defi-synthetic-assetclass-project-governance-mechanisms/20240109/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 14:48:51 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/defi-synthetic-assetclass-project-governance-mechanisms/20240109/</guid>
      <description>Synthetix (SNX): In 2022, Synthetix was considered a leader in the decentralized finance (DeFi) space, with a strong focus on governance and decentralization. The project had plans to transition to a DAO structure and address inefficiencies within its governance system. The goal was to empower the community and ensure a smoother transition to full decentralization.&#xA;Current Status (January 2024): Synthetix has indeed made progress in its journey towards decentralization. The creation of multiple DAOs was an attempt to distribute power more evenly among the community members.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeFi Synthetic AssetClass Project Governance Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/defi-synthetic-assetclass-project-governance-mechanisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 14:48:51 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/posts/defi-synthetic-assetclass-project-governance-mechanisms/</guid>
      <description>Synthetix (SNX): In 2022, Synthetix was considered a leader in the decentralized finance (DeFi) space, with a strong focus on governance and decentralization. The project had plans to transition to a DAO structure and address inefficiencies within its governance system. The goal was to empower the community and ensure a smoother transition to full decentralization.&#xA;Current Status (January 2024): Synthetix has indeed made progress in its journey towards decentralization. The creation of multiple DAOs was an attempt to distribute power more evenly among the community members.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Syntax Guide</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/markdown-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/markdown-syntax/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rich Content</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/rich-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/rich-content/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo ships with several &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/#use-hugos-built-in-shortcodes&#34;&gt;Built-in Shortcodes&lt;/a&gt; for rich content, along with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/about/hugo-and-gdpr/&#34;&gt;Privacy Config&lt;/a&gt; and a set of Simple Shortcodes that enable static and no-JS versions of various social media embeds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emoji Support</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/emoji-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/emoji-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Emoji can be enabled in a Hugo project in a number of ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Math Typesetting</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/math-typesetting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/math-typesetting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mathematical notation in a Hugo project can be enabled by using third party JavaScript libraries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Placeholder Text</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/placeholder-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/placeholder-text/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem est tota propiore conpellat pectoribus de pectora summo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://fatratkiller.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fatratkiller.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>A self-taught full-stack engineer who transitioned midway in my career path. Riding the wave of web3 innovation, I&amp;rsquo;ve had encounters with both devils and angels. My professional journey began as a crypto trader and venture investment manager, and my current interests lie in passive investing and creative IT development.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
